# 新疆·和田
(Hotan, Xinjiang)
# 我们今天是来吃烤肉的（烤全羊）
Today, we came here for whole roasted lamb
# 后面的师傅还在忙
The people behind are still busy
# 天呐
Holy moly!
# 羊就直接这么烤吗
Are lambs roasted simply like this?
# （完成交接）
(Handover finished)
# 这一个炉子 地炉
This oven, this underground oven
# 差不多
Basically
# 直径长就是一步的距离
It's one step in the diameter
# 来 跟着我的镜头 看一看里面的羊
Come, follow my camera and look at the lambs
# 看着这个坑不大
This oven doesn't look big
# 但是里面能够装9只羊
But it's big enough for 9 lambs
# 而每一炉烤熟 就需要两个小时
Every batch takes 2 hours to roast
# 站在这个地方 你都能感受到
Even if you stand here, you can still feel
# 它的温度
its temperature
# 你看这个地方
Look at here
# 它会留出来一些缝隙
Some gaps are left here
# 像这个地方和那个地方
Like here, and over there
# 朝外冒烟
For smoke to come out
# 咱们等一等吧
Let's wait for a while
# 等着烤肉做好了 再点
Wait until the roasted meat is ready to order
# 和我一起等待的还有这么多蜜蜂
And there are so many bees also waiting with me
# 烤全羊要一公斤155块钱
155 yuan for 1kg of whole roasted lamb
# 最低能买多少钱的？
What's the minimum that I can buy?
# 啊？
Huh?
# 我的意思是
I mean
# 最低点多少钱的 有（这样要求）吗
How much should I buy at least? Any requirements?
# 300克可以 400克可以
300g or 400g
# 都可以
Both are fine
# 烤全羊 你自己去那边点
Go there to order the whole roasted lamb
# 自己在那边点
Go there to order?
# 烤全羊去那边点 其他的在我这边点
Go there for whole roasted lamb. Ask me for other stuff
# - 我再要一个酸奶 还有一个那个
# - 一个酸奶
- I'd like a yogurt. And a...
- A yogurt
# - 还有雏鸽拉面是吧
# - 鸽子拉面
- Is there hand pulled noodles with young pigeon?
- Hand pulled noodles with pigeon
# 对
Yeah
# 再要两个这个 然后
Two orders of it. And...
# 待会我去那边点全羊
I'll order the lamb over there later
# 新疆的烤全羊
Whole roasted lamb from Xinjiang
# 坐在这个地方 你能够看到
Sit here, and you can watch
# 一只只全羊 从身边路过
the whole roasted lambs passing by
# 刚才那一只已经卖完了
The previous one is already sold
# 咱们等着新的来 去拿
Let's wait for another one to come
# 这个就是5块钱的酸奶
This is the yogurt for 5 yuan
# 还是有点凉的
It's a little bit cool
# 看很多人都说 新疆的酸奶不错
I heard may people say yogurt in Xinjiang is really good
# 咱们尝一尝手工做出来的酸奶
Let's try this hand-made yogurt
# 是什么样的味道
See how it tastes
# 上面是有一层类似奶皮的
There's something like milk skin at the top
# 无糖酸奶 真的是无糖酸奶
It's plain yogurt. No sugar at all
# （来啦 来啦）
(it's coming) Wow
# 这是抱着一只羊过来的
He just passed by holding a whole lamb
# 哇
Wow
# 这边切好羊排之后 称好羊排之后
They divide and weight the lamb rib
# 要放在馕上面
and then put it on the naans
# 然后再剁 剁 剁
and then chop, chop, chop
# 又来了 又来了 又来了
Coming again! Coming again!
# 多的很 一天卖多少只羊
There's so many. How many do they sell everyday?
# 一公斤的羊排 14号
1kg lamb rib. Number 14
# 哇 谢谢
Wow, thank you
# 咱们要的是烤全羊当中的羊排
We ordered some rib of the whole roasted lamb
# 它是下面放了两个馕
There are two naans at the bottom
# 把全羊放在上面
and the lamb on the top
# 但是站在那个地方
However, when standing over there
# 你能够闻到羊肉的香味
you could already smell the aroma of the lamb
# 就像
It feels like
# 你好像打开了一个锅一样
You opened the lid of a pot
# 瞬间 羊肉的香味扑鼻而来
# 蜜蜂来和我们抢羊肉吃了
The bees are trying to take some of our lamb
# 这次咱们先不吃肉 先吃这个皮
Instead of the meat, let's try the skin first
# 感觉这个皮 特别诱人
The skin feels especially appealing
# （脆脆的外皮）
(crispy skin)
# 它这个烤全羊 外面的皮就是咸香的
The skin of the roasted lamb feels salty and aromatic
# 但是里面还是比较嫩的
But the meat inside is still rather tender
# 没有很重的咸味
and not very salty
# 这个皮烤的像纸一样薄
The skin is as thin as paper thanks to the roasting
# 但是薄脆的外皮下
However, there's fat and lean lamb meat interleaved
# 裹着肥瘦相间的羊肉
wrapped underneath the crispy and thin skin
# 你如果说
Just in case
# 撕一点皮来吃
you tear some skin and put it in your mouth
# 真的会满嘴流油
the oil would leak from your mouth
# 如果说觉得 （直接吃肉）吃腻了呢
In case you feel greasy (for having meat only)
# 就是撕点馕 配着羊肉来吃
just grab some naan and eat it with the lamb
# 咱们要的是肋排 所以说 骨头很多
As we ordered rib, there's a lot of bones
# 吃骨头上的肉 比较带劲一些
It's quite chewy to have the meat on the bones
# 是不是可以下手抓
Maybe I should use my hands
# 感觉下手抓 好像更直接一些
It feels more straightforward with my hands
# 吃肉最大的乐趣 就是直接上手抓
Using your bare hands is the most enjoyment when having meat
# 烤全羊上来的时候
When a whole roasted lamb is ready
# 你可以自己选择它的部位
you may choose which part to order
# 如果想吃肥一点的 像我们要的肋排
If you want something fat, you may order the rib like us
# 如果说 想吃瘦一点的
Or, if you want a leaner part
# 可以要腿上的肉 也是很好的
You may order the leg. It's also good
# 像咱就是要了两斤
We only ordered 1kg
# 但有的人真的会要一只
However, some may order a whole lamb
# 很多人围在一起吃烤全羊
to be shared by a full party of people
# 这个就是 真的没有一点的甜味
This is like... There's no sweetness at all
# 但是有这种奶香味
But only the aromatic flavor of milk
# （关注雪鱼探店）
(Subscribe)